Pragnya Paramita

3 9731037293

⋈ pp.pragnya@gmail.com

Android Development

OBJECTIVE

To carve a niche for myself in design and development of solution, system and application through my expertise in a creative and challenging organization while enabling further personal and professional development.

SUMMARY

An android developer with experience in requirement analysis, development, have a sharp eye for detail, quality, deadline, prioritizing tasks and have experience working through out software life cycle with capabilities to own independent modules as well as working with a team.

POSITIONS

8/2012 – current | Senior Software Engineer at BORQS Software Solutions, https://www.borqs.com/ Responsible for requirement analysis, development, integration, enhancement, bug fixing of Application, Application widgets and UIFramework components on Android

Skills: Android 4.0-6.0, JSON and Core JAVA

7/2008 – 7/2010 | Assistant Systems Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services, https://www.tcs.com Responsible for Software development for computerization of Thermal Power plant. Skills: Core Java, oracle database and sql

EDUCATION

7/2010 - 7/2012 MTech in IT in (Networking and Mobile Computing), (IIITB)International Institute Of Information Technology, Bangalore

CGPA: 3.68/4

7/2004 - 6/2008 BTech in Electrical, College Of Engineering And Technology, Bhubaneswar, Biju Patnaik University Of Technology

CGPA: 8.45/10

SKILLS

Mobile Platform | Android 4.0 -6.0

Programming Core Java, JSON, SQL

Tech- Android UI and Framework.

nology and Domain (Activity, Apps/Sevices, BroadcastReceiver, Intent, Asynctask/Thread/Handler, App Wid-

get, Email Framework)

PROJECTS

3/2016 – current | Theme application : Android + Feature Apps, BORQS Software Solutions

- Responsible for development of Theme application which can apply theme independently across android applications at runtime based on Sony's Runtime Resource Overlay concepts.
- Technology: Android Marshmallow 6.0 and Android Studio

10/2014 – current | **Operator pack customization**, As a consultant with Qualcomm innovation center for America Movil, Telcel, Claro, Vodafone, Telefonica, Orange

- Responsible for requirement analysis, FR scoping design, development and integration of different operator specific customization and feature requirements for Platform and Framework and UI components and operator specific pack creation for Latin America and Europe region for Qualcomm snapdragon chipset specific device.
- Developed network blocking app for Prepaid SIM with zero balance for different opera-
- Technology: Android Lolipop 5.0, Android Marshmallow 6.0 Version control: Git and Gerrit.

6/2014 – 9/2014 | Android + Feature Apps and Widgets, BORQS Software Solutions for Karbon, Panasonic,

- Responsible for development of Weather Widget, Weather App for Tile Based Launcher, Theme Manager.
- Technology: Android Kitkat 4.4

11/2013 – 5/2014 | Sonim XP6, BORQS Software Solutions. for AT&T & Sonim Technologies.

- Responsible for development of Weather Widget, Email framework customization, customer feature addition in Launcher screen, and base issue fixing in UI Framework Components.
- Technology: Android Jelly Bean 4.3. and Android Kitkat 4.4

6/2013 – 10/2013 | Custom Android + UI Component Design, BORQS Software Solutions for Internal

- Responsible for development and enhancement of android baselist view and grid view widget to a custom pinned header list view and grid view which can be used across applications for ICS Android.
- Technology: Android ICS 4.0.

8/2012 – 6/2013 | AT&T NEC Terrain, BORQS Software Solutions for AT&T, NEC

- Responsible for enhancement and base issue fixing in UI framework and base Email framework.
- Technology: Android ICS 4.0.

7/2008 – 7/2010 | Computerization of Thermal Power Plant, Tata Consultancy Services for Punjab State **Electricity Board**

- Responsible for development of Operation and Management Module and client site train-
- Technology:XML, J developer,PL/SQL, Crystal Report

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recipient of the merit scholarship (top 5 in each branch) for the excellence of academics in B. Tech for three consecutive years 2005, 2006, 2007.
- Worked as **Teaching Assistant** in IIITB during Mtech.